Mark Barone

720 Glastonbury Court, Cumming GA 30041

Mobile: 404-422-7129

Email: mark@mark-barone.com

github.com/baronema

= mark-barone.com

in linkedin.com/in/mark-barone-546128145

ENTRY LEVEL SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SUMMARY

Seven plus years of experience with the proven ability to diagnose, troubleshoot, and resolve technical problems in a time sensitive/high stress environment. Exceptional customer service and communication skills; consistently conveys competence and attentiveness while engaging with clients and co-workers alike.

PROJECTS

Bookshelf - An intra-classroom library management and loan app built using Node.js, Express, MongoDB

- Implemented an authentication system for login and library loans using the Passport NPM package
- Created custom ISBN lookup search bar to automate new book additions by utilizing Node-ISBN API
- Developed MongoDB schema for data persistence hosted via mLab subscription

Assessment Tool – An observation-based assessment platform for tracking early learning development

- Designed custom user interface according to teacher recommendations using the JavaFX library
- Created an authentication server for user login requests passed over a multithreaded socket connection
- Increased teacher efficiency by eliminating paper-based recording of student assessments

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java | C++ | JavaScript | jQuery | Node.js | Express | HTML | CSS

WORK HISTORY

IT Field Technician, 10/2017 to 3/2018

Brooksource - Roswell, GA

• Responsible for the I.T. infrastructure upgrade of more than 2000 assets at North Fulton WellStar Hospital as part of the hospitals EPIC System integration, helping to achieve a successful Go-Live within a 12-month period

Engineering Technician III, 02/2012 – 01/2013

CGI Federal – Jacksonville, NC

• Established an onsite component level repair shop greatly improving the number of available replacement processing units and displays on hand, thus reducing item procurement and shipping costs by 30%

Communications Technician, 11/2005 to 04/2011

United States Marine Corps – Kaneohe Bay, HI

 Performed diagnostic testing and troubleshooting of various communications equipment, managed help desk tickets, and maintained equipment inventory and maintenance logs

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, 2014 to 2017

Regis University - Denver, CO

Graduated Magna Cum Laude (3.75 / 4.0)

Courses included:

Modern Software Engineering Co Java Development Da

Computer Systems Security Data Networks Object-Oriented Development

Unix OS